Class of 1883 Records, 1875-1998
Smith College Archives
Class of 1883 Records
1875-1998
Smith College. Class of 1883.
RG 80 UUID:9359cfb5-34e9-4e94-af62-b2287aaaf585
16 boxes (6.75 linear ft.)
Smith College Archives Northampton, MA
This collection contains black and white photographs, letters, correspondence, cards, memorabilia, scrapbooks, journals, albums, student's notes and work, newspaper clippings, and information about the commencement and reunions of the Class of 1883.
The Class of 1883 was the fifth graduating class of Smith College.
The Class of 1883 Records contain materials describing the history of the Class of 1883. Types of materials include black and white photographs, letters, correspondence, cards, memorabilia, scrapbooks, journals, albums, student's notes and work, newspaper clippings, and information about the commencement and reunions of the Class of 1883.
Information on Use
Terms of Access and Use
The records are open for research according to the regulations of the Smith College Archives without any additional restrictions.
History of the Collection
The Class of 1883 Records were created by the students and donated to the College Archives.
- Class of 1883: Baccalaureate Service 1883 (Box 1400, Folder 1)
- Class of 1883: Commencement 1883 (Box 1400, Folder 2)
- Class of 1883: Commencement Speaker 1883 (Box 1400, Folder 3)
- Class of 1883: Commencement Music 1883 (Box 1400, Folder 4)
- Class of 1883: Photograph List 1883 (Box 1400, Folder 5)
- Class of 1883: Elm 1883, 1889, 1915, 1917-21 (Box 1400, Folder 6)
- Class of 1883: Class-German 1883 (Box 1400, Folder 7)
- Class of 1883: History 1881-83, 1936-37 (Box 1400, Folder 8)
- Class of 1883: Peacocks 1913 (Box 1400, Folder 9)
- Class of 1883: Senior Party 1883 (Box 1400, Folder 10)
- Class of 1883: Senior Reception 1883 (Box 1400, Folder 11)
- Class of 1883: Sophomore Reception 1879 (Box 1400, Folder 12)
- Class of 1883: Class Letters 1883, 1912, 1915, 1918-20, 1923, 1925, 1929, 1935, 1940, 1944, 1951 (Box 1400, Folder 13)
- Class of 1883: Songs 1883 (Box 1400, Folder 14)
- Class of 1883: Class Supper 1883 (Box 1400, Folder 15)
- Class of 1883: Group Photos 1883 (Box 1400, Folder 16)
- Class of 1883: Seat 1919-20, 1933 (Box 1400, Folder 17)
- Class of 1883: Senior Dramatics 1880, 1883 (Box 1400, Folder 18)
- Class of 1883: Sundial 1932-33 (Box 1400, Folder 19)
- Class of 1883: "Weep" 1883 (Box 1400, Folder 20)
- Class of 1883: Reunions (Photos) 1915, 1941, undated (Box 1401, Folder 1)
- Class of 1883: Reunion (1889) 1889 (Box 1401, Folder 2)
- Class of 1883: Reunion (1893) 1893 (Box 1401, Folder 3)
- Class of 1883: Reunion (1898) 1898 (Box 1401, Folder 4)
- Class of 1883: Reunion (1903) 1903 (Box 1401, Folder 5)
- Class of 1883: Reunion (1908) 1908 (Box 1401, Folder 6)
- Class of 1883: Reunion (1913) 1913 (Box 1401, Folder 7)
- Class of 1883: Reunion (1923) 1923 (Box 1401, Folder 8)
- Class of 1883: Reunion (1928) 1928 (Box 1401, Folder 9)
- Class of 1883: Reunion (1933) 1933 (Box 1401, Folder 10)
- Class of 1883: Reunion (1938) 1938 (Box 1401, Folder 11)
- Class of 1883: Reunion (1943, 1948) 1943, 1948 (Box 1401, Folder 12)
- Class of 1883: Reunion Songs undated (Box 1401, Folder 13)
- Class of 1883: Aldrich, Annette Howland (Photographs) 1883 (Box 1402, Folder 1)
- Class of 1883: Allen, Mabel 1882, 1938 (Box 1402, Folder 2)
- Class of 1883: Allen, Mabel (Correspondence, Sept-Jan) 1879-80 (Box 1402, Folder 3)
- Class of 1883: Allen, Mabel (Correspondence, Jan-Jun) 1880 (Box 1402, Folder 4)
- Class of 1883: Allen, Mabel (Correspondence, Sept-Jan) 1880-81 (Box 1402, Folder 5)
- Class of 1883: Allen, Mabel (Correspondence, Jan-Jun) 1881 (Box 1402, Folder 6)
- Class of 1883: Allen, Mabel (Correspondence, Oct-Mar) 1881-82 (Box 1402, Folder 7)
- Class of 1883: Allen, Mabel (Correspondence, Mar-May) 1882-83 (Box 1402, Folder 8)
- Class of 1883: Allen, Mabel (Essays) 1881 (Box 1402, Folder 9)
- Class of 1883: Allen, Mabel (Journal) 1879-82 (Box 1402, Folder 10)
- Class of 1883: Allen, Mabel (Memorabilia) 1880-83 (Box 1402, Folder 11)
- Class of 1883: Allen, Mabel (Photographs) 1880-82 (Box 1402, Folder 12)
- Class of 1883: Anthony, Mary Stuart 1883 (Box 1402, Folder 13)
- Class of 1883: Anthony, Mary Stuart (Photographs) 1897, undated (Box 1402, Folder 14)
- Class of 1883: Barrett, Minnie Lincoln (Photographs of Family, Northampton, Monson) 1899, undated (Box 1402, Folder 15)
- Class of 1883: Bates, Emma (Box 1402, Folder 16)
- Class of 1883: Bodman, Clara Philena 1889, 1915, 1917, 1929, undated (Box 1402, Folder 17)
- Class of 1883: Bodman, Clara Philena (Photographs) 1954, undated (Box 1402, Folder 18)
- Class of 1883: Bowen, Julia Anna (Photographs, etc) 1880, undated (Box 1402, Folder 19)
- Class of 1883: Brooks, Frona Marie 1881, 1883, 1937, undated (Box 1402, Folder 20)
- Class of 1883: Brooks, Frona Marie (Correspondence, Apr-Mar) 1880-83 (Box 1402, Folder 21)
- Class of 1883: Brooks, Frona Marie (Correspondence, Undated College Years) undated (Box 1402, Folder 22)
- Class of 1883: Brooks, Frona Marie (Photographs, etc) 1883-84, 1888, 1891, 1917, 1947, undated (Box 1402, Folder 23)
- Class of 1883: Bush, Sally (Photographs) 1883 (Box 1402, Folder 24)
- Class of 1883: Clark, Mary Annie 1878, 1883, 1936 (Box 1403, Folder 1)
- Class of 1883: Converse, Clara Adra 1883, 1902, 1923-24, 1929, 2003 (Box 1403, Folder 2)
- Class of 1883: Daniels, Susan Elizabeth 1883, 1910, undated (Box 1403, Folder 3)
- Class of 1883: Dickinson, Eveline 1883, 1927, undated (Box 1403, Folder 4)
- Class of 1883: Dike, Florence Blanchard 1883, 1919, 1923 (Box 1403, Folder 5)
- Class of 1883: Dunton, Ada Lamira 1883 (Box 1403, Folder 6)
- Class of 1883: Eames, Ella Florence 1883, 1895, undated (Box 1403, Folder 7)
- Class of 1883: Edgarton, L. 1882-83, undated (Box 1403, Folder 8)
- Class of 1883: Fine, Jean Gurney 1880, 1883, 1892, 1912, 1935 (Box 1403, Folder 9)
- Class of 1883: Flynt, Ella Eudocia 1880, undated (Box 1403, Folder 10)
- Class of 1883: Forman, Evelyn Jean 1880-1883 (Box 1403, Folder 11)
- Class of 1883: Gifford, Alice Eliza 1883 (Box 1404, Folder 1)
- Class of 1883: Gilmore, Evelyn Langdon 1883, 1956, undated (Box 1404, Folder 2)
- Class of 1883: Gleason, Clara Belle 1883, 1939, 1947 (Box 1404, Folder 3)
- Class of 1883: Griswold, Louise Darling 1882 (Box 1404, Folder 4)
- Class of 1883: Gulliver, Charlotte Chester 1880, 1883, 1925, 1927 (Box 1404, Folder 5)
- Class of 1883: Gulliver, Charlotte Chester (Scholarship) 1927, 1929 (Box 1404, Folder 6)
- Class of 1883: Hall, Mira Hinsdale 1883, 1932-33, 1937 (Box 1404, Folder 7)
- Class of 1883: Hall, Mira Hinsdale (Correspondence) 1879-1880 (Box 1404, Folder 8)
- Class of 1883: Hall, Mira Hinsdale (Correspondence) 1881-82, undated (Box 1404, Folder 9)
- Class of 1883: Haire, Anna Roberta 1883 (Box 1404, Folder 10)
- Class of 1883: Hanna, Annie 1883, 1997 (Box 1404, Folder 11)
- Class of 1883: Haring, Mary Elma 1883 (Box 1404, Folder 12)
- Class of 1883: Harris, Clara Elizabeth 1883 (Box 1404, Folder 13)
- Class of 1883: Harris, Henrietta 1883, 1933 (Box 1404, Folder 14)
- Class of 1883: Harris, Henrietta (Letters) 1881 (Box 1404, Folder 15)
- Class of 1883: Harrison, Florence Marguerite 1883 (Box 1404, Folder 16)
- Class of 1883: Henry, Esther Maria 1879, undated (Box 1404, Folder 17)
- Class of 1883: Hilliard, Caroline Elizabeth 1883 (Box 1404, Folder 18)
- Class of 1883: Hine, Edith Caroline 1883 (Box 1404, Folder 19)
- Class of 1883: Holmes, Esther Reynolds 1883 (Box 1404, Folder 20)
- Class of 1883: Johnson, Elizabeth Frances 1883, 1917, undated (Box 1404, Folder 21)
- Class of 1883: Latimer, Mary Pelton (Photographs) 1880 (Box 1405, Folder 1)
- Class of 1883: Lawrence, Elizabeth Crocker (Box 1408)
- Class of 1883: Leach, Edith (Photographs) 1882-83 (Box 1405, Folder 3)
- Class of 1883: Leonard, Anne Louise (Photographs, etc.) 1883, 1928 (Box 1405, Folder 4)
- Class of 1883: Machado, Salomé Amelia 1885, 1879 (Box 1405, Folder 5)
- Class of 1883: Machado, Salomé Amelia (Photographs) 1880-83, 1923, 1954 (Box 1405, Folder 6)
- Class of 1883: Marsh, Carrie Amelia (Letters) 1905-06, 1938, 1942 (Box 1405, Folder 7)
- Class of 1883: Marsh, Carrie Amelia (Photographs) 1882-83 (Box 1405, Folder 8)
- Class of 1883: Marvin, Anna Humphreys (Photographs) 1882, 1885 (Box 1405, Folder 9)
- Class of 1883: Mead, Sara Elizabeth (Photographs) 1879-83 (Box 1406, Folder 1)
- Class of 1883: Miller, Alice Mason (Photographs, etc.) 1882-83, 1895, 1932 (Box 1406, Folder 2)
- Class of 1883: Montgomery, Lizzie (Photographs) 1881, 1883 (Box 1406, Folder 3)
- Class of 1883: Morse, Anna Louisa (Photographs, etc.) 1883, 1938, 1979, undated (Box 1406, Folder 4)
- Class of 1883: Nordhoff, Amy Davis (Photographs) 1883 (Box 1406, Folder 5)
- Class of 1883: Osgood, Margarette Manton (Letters) 1879-83, 1887, 1938 (Box 1406, Folder 6)
- Class of 1883: Osgood, Margarette Manton(Photographs) 1882-83 (Box 1406, Folder 7)
- Class of 1883: Palmer, Clara Frances(Photographs, etc.) 1882-83, 1938 (Box 1406, Folder 8)
- Class of 1883: Palmes, Nannie Gertrude 1883 (Box 1406, Folder 9)
- Class of 1883: Parker, Julia F. (Photographs) 1882-83 (Box 1406, Folder 10)
- Class of 1883: Parker, Mary (Photographs) undated (Box 1406, Folder 11)
- Class of 1883: Payne, Ella (Photographs) 1883 (Box 1406, Folder 12)
- Class of 1883: Phillips, Maria (Photographs) undated (Box 1406, Folder 13)
- Class of 1883: Poore, Harriet Paul (Photographs) 1883 (Box 1406, Folder 14)
- Class of 1883: Rice, Mary Katrine (Photographs) 1880, 1883 (Box 1406, Folder 15)
- Class of 1883: Robbins, Jane Elizabeth (Photographs, etc.) 1880, 1883, 1912, 1925, 1930, undated (Box 1406, Folder 16)
- Class of 1883: Rogers, Sarah Philena (Photographs) 1880 (Box 1406, Folder 17)
- Class of 1883: Scott, Jennie Louise (Photographs) 1879-80 (Box 1406, Folder 18)
- Class of 1883: Smith, Clara Janet Augusta 1883 (Box 1406, Folder 19)
- Class of 1883: Smith, Lucy Hannah (Photographs, etc.) 1883, 1898, 1942 (Box 1406, Folder 20)
- Class of 1883: Snow, Florence (Photographs) 1883 (Box 1406, Folder 21)
- Class of 1883: Snow, Florence (English Papers) 1890 (Box 1406, Folder 22)
- Class of 1883: Stephens, Minnie Florence (Photographs, etc.) 1883, undated (Box 1406, Folder 23)
- Class of 1883: Stetson, Ella Carleton (Photographs) 1881-82 (Box 1406, Folder 24)
- Class of 1883: Story, Frances Rebecca (Photographs) 1883 (Box 1406, Folder 25)
- Class of 1883: Taylor, Martha Skinner (Photographs, etc.) 1879-81, 1883, 1929, undated (Box 1407, Folder 1)
- Class of 1883: Thaxter, Louise Godfrey (Photographs) 1882-83 (Box 1407, Folder 2)
- Class of 1883: Tilden, Laura Bugbee (Photographs) 1883 (Box 1407, Folder 3)
- Class of 1883: Tilton, Annie Eugenia (Photographs) 1882-83 (Box 1407, Folder 4)
- Class of 1883: Van Ausdal, Mary (Photographs) 1883 (Box 1407, Folder 5)
- Class of 1883: Waldron, Elizabeth (Photographs, etc.) 1880, 1883, 1928 (Box 1407, Folder 6)
- Class of 1883: Ward, Alice (Photographs, etc.) 1883, 1906, undated (Box 1407, Folder 7)
- Class of 1883: Ward, Alice (Publications) 1883, 1888, 1890-91, 1893, 1905, 1907, 1919 (Box 1407, Folder 8)
- Class of 1883: Welles, Mary Crowell (Box 1407, Folder 9)
- Class of 1883: Wheeler, Mabel Sarah (Photographs) 1881, 1883 (Box 1407, Folder 10)
- Class of 1883: White, Mary Avery (Photographs, etc.) 1883, 1898, 1916 (Box 1407, Folder 11)
- Class of 1883: Willard, Abby Gregory 1879-80 (Box 1407, Folder 12)
- Class of 1883: Willard, Abby Gregory 1942 (Box 1407, Folder 13)
- Class of 1883: Willard, Abby Gregory (Photographs, etc.) 1879, 1887, undated (Box 1407, Folder 14)
- Class of 1883: Willard, Charlotte Richards 1898-99, 1906-08, 1910, 1913-14, 1918, 1921 (Box 1407, Folder 15)
- Class of 1883: Willard, Charlotte Richards (Photographs) 1883 (Box 1407, Folder 16)
- Class of 1883: Williams, Cora May (Photographs, etc.) 1883, 1926 (Box 1407, Folder 17)
- Class of 1883: Wilson, Flora Emeline (Photographs) 1883 (Box 1407, Folder 18)
- Class of 1883: Wilson, Nellie Frances 1880 (Box 1407, Folder 19)
- Class of 1883: Winsor, Mary Pickard undated (Box 1407, Folder 20)
- Class of 1883: Wolcott, Clara Gertrude (Photographs, etc.) 1883, 1939 (Box 1407, Folder 21)
- Class of 1883: Woodward, Ida Minette (Correspondence) 1880, 1882-83 (Box 1407, Folder 22)
- Class of 1883: Woodward, Ida Minette (Photographs) 1883, 1890, 1933 (Box 1407, Folder 23)
- Class of 1883: Woodward, Louise (Photographs) 1883 (Box 1407, Folder 24)
- Class of 1883: Yale, Gertrude (Photographs) 1883 (Box 1407, Folder 25)
- Class of 1883: Mather, Mary H. Askew 1881-83, 1886, 1968, undated (Box 1413, Folder 1)
- Class of 1883: Mather, Mary H. Askew (Journal) 1882-83 (Box 1413, Folder 2)
- Class of 1883: Mather, Mary H. Askew (Journal, Jan-June) 1882 (Box 1413, Folder 3)
- Class of 1883: Mather, Mary H. Askew (Journal, Sept-Dec) 1882 (Box 1413, Folder 4)
- Class of 1883: Miller, Alice Mason (Letters) 1876-78, 1880-83, 1948-49 (Box 1414, Folder 1)
- Class of 1883: Miller, Alice Mason (Correspondence to Family, Sept-Oct) 1877 (Box 1414, Folder 2)
- Class of 1883: Miller, Alice Mason (Correspondence to Family, Nov-Dec) 1877 (Box 1414, Folder 3)
- Class of 1883: Miller, Alice Mason (Correspondence to Family, Jan-June) 1878 (Box 1414, Folder 4)
- Class of 1883: Miller, Alice Mason (Correspondence to Family, Sept-Nov) 1882 (Box 1414, Folder 5)
- Class of 1883: Miller, Alice Mason (Correspondence to Family, Jan-June) 1883 (Box 1414, Folder 6)
- Class of 1883: Photo Album undated (Box 1414.1)